thetool.io 2018-06-28

# Privacy Policy - TheTool

## Privacy Policy for the TheTool Website

Your privacy is important to us, and we are taking the responsibility to protect your personal information. We have updated our Privacy Policy in accordance with the new **General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)** that comes into effect on 25 May 2018.

This Privacy Policy regulates the collection and processing of personal data that are provided by Users, when they access, browse or make use of the features on the Website accessible from the URL: [https://thetool.io](https://thetool.io/) (hereinafter, the website).

When for the use or request of any service it is necessary to provide personal data, users will guarantee its veracity, accuracy, authenticity and validity. In this sense, it will be the obligation of users to keep the data updated in a way that corresponds to reality at all times.

### Data collection, purposes, legitimation basis and conservation periods

The acceptance of this Privacy Policy means that the User authorizes Shutapp Projects, S.L. with NIF B66076829 (hereinafter, Shutapp), and address at Calle Provença 314, 2nd floor, 08037, Barcelona (Spain), as owner of the Website, to process your data and include them in a record of treatments of your responsibility , for the purposes stipulated below:

#### a.​ Contact

The User can contact with Shutapp, through the forms established for this purpose on the Website. To do this, you must provide Shutapp with information about the type of query, your name and surnames, the country from which you are consulting, your e-mail address, telephone number, and the reason for the inquiry you wish to make. Shutapp will use this data to process the query and contact the User. This treatment is based on your consent, with the data kept for one year.

#### b.​ Subscription

By registering in TheTool, it will be necessary for the User to provide their identifying information, such as name, surname and email, for the processing of the subscription.

​The legitimation base for the treatment of such data is based on the execution of the contract.

​The period for keeping the data will be adequate to comply with the contractual obligations and, in any case, up to five more years for tax procedures and to cover possible liabilities, unless other terms are applicable.

#### c. ​Blog

The user can make comments on the blog of TheTool (<https://thetool.io/blog>). The treatment of these data will have the sole purpose of managing the publication on the blog. This treatment is based on consent. The comments made by the User will remain permanently on the Website, unless he requests their deletion.

#### d. ​Cookies

The Website has technology for the implementation of files called cookies on the computer that is used for accessing and browsing the Website. Cookies can be blocked or disabled at any time through the browser’s configuration options, and are used to improve your browsing experience on our website, analyze user navigation and be able to offer personalized content. If you want more information you can consult our Cookies Policy.

​The legitimation base for the treatment of such data is based on the consent of the User.

### Advertising purposes and special treatments

#### a.​ Advertising

If the User expressly authorizes it, Shutapp may send advertising of its services, such as news of its products. The User may revoke such consent at any time through the email [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or through any other means designed for this purpose that would have been included in the communications sent. The legitimation base for the treatment of such data is based on the consent of the User.

​The term of conservation of the data will be of the time that remains registered in our system for the sending of publicity or of 12 months from the last time that the User interacts with Shutapp.

### Exercise of rights

Likewise, the User may revoke the consent to the processing, exercising the rights of access, rectification, deletion, portability, opposition and limitation to the treatment, informing Shutapp through an email addressed to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection) or indicating it to the physical address indicated above, indicating as subject “Data Protection”. In both cases, the communication must be accompanied by any official document that allows identification, to prevent access to your data by third parties.

At any time, the User may submit a claim to the control authority.

### Modification of the Privacy Policy

Shutapp reserves the right to modify its Privacy Policy at any time, respecting the current legislation on data protection and prior communication to the interested parties.  
Language applicable to this Privacy Policy.

The language applicable to this Privacy Policy is Spanish. Any version of the same in a different language is offered for the convenience of the User and to facilitate its understanding. However, this Privacy Policy will always be governed by its version in Spanish.

In case of contradiction between the Privacy Policy in any language and its Spanish version, the Spanish version will prevail.

**Date of last  update:**  
This agreement was last updated on May 18, 2018.

Link to Spanish version
